2022 marks the beginning of season three
of the vlog after nearly 200 episodes
in the first two seasons after a long awaited
year we are finally able to get up in the sky
with powder bird heli skiing and enjoy a
near perfect day in the wasatch mountains
morning squad second episode of season three here
and it's gonna be a big one i've been looking
forward to this day really since last year when
if you guys remember we didn't get a chance to
fly in the helicopter because of the weather and
so everything basically got postponed until the
next year because there wasn't anything else open
we're to be heading out to powder bird heli skiing
right outside of snowbird i don't want to be late
at all so i'm going to start to get a move on here
i slept in walmart last night so i'm going to get
out of here and then head up to little cottonwoods
powder bird beautiful morning
good morning good morning how you guys
doing how are you good all right lucas
what does it say you are 176.
yeah and you are all set so
thank you so much okay cool looks like you
guys have your waiver signed and everything
okay so right on dig in okay let us know
if you guys need anything cool thank you
all right just a quick morning check-in uh they
had to take my weight i was like 176. so i'm sure
they'll be doing that for everyone in the bird but
i got to get all my gear out i've been taking my
boots out from yesterday so everything's going
to be quite quite wet still so get this going
so we had to start today with a nice
breakfast they made some potatoes eggs
almost everything we would
make in the van ourselves so
i haven't ate this morning so i was banking on
this this is a big move and i think they also
will get lunch at the end of the day but like i've
said before it's gonna be a beautiful day blue sky
um and it's my favorite parts of the day with
the alpine go at the top of the mountain so
all in all just beautiful i mean
look at this yeah look at that food
most people like to put this on at the beginning
of the day and leave it on to get in and out
of the helicopter but if you want if it's too
uncomfortable for you and it pushes you forward
too much just let your guide know and your guide
will be fine taking it on and off and putting it
in the basket then you just have to put it on
at the top of each rod at the top of the run
we're gonna do what's called arming the airbag
system and this little deal here you don't want
to pull on this i'll tell you why in a second but
you just expose it so at the top of the run we
help each other and say hey unzip your airbag now
it's armed okay what happens is if you're skiing
along and you get caught in an avalanche you
can pull this trigger and a big airbag comes out
over the back of your head and the theory is it
gives you a much better chance of ending up on
top of the snow but when you're skiing if you
happen to feel your skis getting sucked down
the hill against your will or your snowboard
what you really want to do first thing is
drop your poles and just try to ski off of it
to the left or to the right just try to ski off
of it sometimes you can okay if you can't you'll
know pretty quick that you're getting sucked down
hill a little bit and you're like okay i'm not
going to be able to ski out of this pull the
airbag and it's really really revolutionized
the avalanche safety world quite a bit a lot
a lot of people end up on top of the snow instead
of underneath system doesn't guarantee it but it
gives you a much better chance got done with the
little safety briefing where they kind of tell
you what's in the pack all the things like that
so we just got our avalanche beacons in case you
do get buried this is a way to kind of locate
people so just turned it on it's on transmitted
unfortunately i can't bring the big camera this
won't fit in the avalanche bag so everything from
here now it's gonna be on the gopro and we are
gonna head out and do the helicopter briefing
and then start to start to get up in the air
so got everything kind of loaded up i think
so let's go
i'm gonna ask for your attention here what i'm
gonna do is kind of talk about strapping our skis
and moving to the helicopter and also what
i'm gonna talk about is how we're gonna
and if you could just uh turn that
off right now and yeah let's just
they basically broke us up into three different
groups i believe we're all gonna be skiing
together but just in terms of the helicopter only
four people can fit in the helicopter with a guide
in the pilot so i am group three so the first
group just went out and then they're basically
gonna drop them off and pick up the next group
so we'll be going out here momentarily and we
kind of have a designated guide i believe his
name is logan and that's really the day i think
we can expect six to seven runs but other than
that i'm stoked the helicopter is probably going
to be even sicker than the actual skiing itself
so just really excited and not much more to say
oh
dude
uh
oh
ah
great
i'll do a right boundary okay because the
right boundary works really well because
we're not going fall line off in that
direction ultimately we're sweeping back
to this sub-bridge down here so i'll go ahead
and put a far right out there that'll be the
right boundary stay left of that you can also
ski just to the right of these tracks that'll
leave us a big patch out there and then you'll
see all these tracks kind of migrate back and
i'll be down there in a big spot down there
okay okay first gear just left of logan copy
look at this
oh my god it's just so crispy first drop oh
oh yeah that'll work that was good yeah
yeah really creamy totally that's awesome
this time of year you can ski pow on
the south aspects it's awesome okay
uh
the first run is in the books it was pretty
mellow up at the top but uh snow was really good
nice little warm-up run and then we kind of got a
little bit more trees as we came down it's kind of
like three phases to get down but first one's
done now we're at the pickup point and we are
waiting for the heli to come
back pick us up and bring us
to the next spot so a truly beautiful day out
here bluebird day and i can hear the helicopter
okay good to go all right
thanks man see you down there
so
just a little bit flat
lily
look at this guys just like untracked i mean
that's nice
so
we are about to do our third run every
run has been at a different zone which
has been pretty sick and snow is just
great there's like a a nice layer on
the bottom with probably three or four
inches on the top and just untracked
cream it feels like so the jj's like always are
just doing really well okay guys so we're gonna
start trending a little right now trending
right just follow me and take your time
i don't know where his line went
oh
oh perfect 360 run look at these trees
sketch trees
so
we got me
one nation
so
um
logan's working through the the little
aspen's there so again when you get in
that stuff just slow down just ski in control
for me please okay and next few years good to go
um
oh this one's a long one
uh
he's calling me
look at just how beautiful it is where we
are i don't know obviously where we are at
but we dropped us off um as the day's
kind of winding down more into the sun
because we were kind of up in the shade a little
bit more but now we're just like in this pure
empty bowl i mean just look at how beautiful all
this is and i'm just standing on top of it right
now so we've been like the lead group so we've
been getting picked up and dropped off first and
then we kind of wait for the next group to come in
behind us i mean just look at this it's like fake
uh
get those assets work those hands
oh it's just so creamy yeah stay in
front of me right there yeah yeah
oh nice and mellow over the
tree oh that was sick no
edo
that was dope oh that was beautiful
okay that's enough oh it's still
going where are we going left
oh beautiful just soak it all in
oh yeah
oh
no it's hurt
one day
um
what a sick day sick day sick day dude
that was so cool okay guys so just like the
stay nice and close right by the gear okay
there you go
here let's
the day is over we ended up
doing six runs which was what we
expected to do i would say compared
to this stuff in alaska it wasn't as
intense or big it felt like um we're almost still
just like skiing the same terrain that you would
find at snowbird or something like that but it
was still really cool to be up in the helicopter
and all that sort of good stuff so
yeah check out what they got for lunch
i literally have steak with asparagus
and a salad and a lot more stuff but steak i mean
come on this is well needed after a day like today
huge thank you to the guides logan and pat and
cam all those guys who just made sure everyone
was safe it's not an easy job with all those
people and running multiple fights things like
that but also big up so it's the whole powder bird
operation i think we are gonna have one more heli
day this year i'm not sure if it's gonna be in
february or march but we will be back there's
a good sort of opener uh to the to the year then
hopefully when we come back we'll be able to do a
little bit more um more advanced terrain and just
stuff that has more pitch to it but all in all
i figure out just how long it can take to
get out of little cottonwood canyon at four
o'clock on a sunday so thank you guys for
watching the second episode of season three
and i will see all of you guys in the next
episode hopefully from jackson hole peace out